John Cohen collection, circa 1939-2019
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 4. Accrual from January 2020, 1939-2019
  - Subseries 11. Digital content, ca. 1980-2013
    - Q'eros: Quechua Music and Rituals, Undated, afc2011059_dc026; 1 DVD-R; 7 files (Box 84)
    - "Hobart Smith's Choice Piece," Stephen Wade, Word 97 A:\hobartIII, April 2000, afc2011059_dc031; 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch); 1 file (Box 84)
      Hobart Smith and Texas Gladden: notes on CDs, Stephen Wade, writing about "Cuckoo Bird," Hobart Smith's "choice piece."
    - Final Traces of the Abstract Expressionists, 2013, afc2011059_dc039; 1 DVD-R; 9 files (Box 84)
      Documentary film by Caro Jost. Includes John Cohen's photography. "#19 written on item."
    - Yazoo: Kentucky booklet images, 2003, afc2011059_dc040; 1 CD-R; 37 files (Box 84)
      Photographic images from Yazoo Records releases.
    - Blues, Ballads, and Bluegrass: copy from Dr. Film transfer, Undated, afc2011059_dc041; 1 DVD-R; 8 files (Box 84)
      Video files from Alan Lomax's film, Ballads, Blues, & Bluegrass.
    - Blues, Ballads, and Bluegrass: George Pickow, Port Washington, Undated, afc2011059_dc042; 1 DVD-R; 8 files (Box 84)
      Blues and Bluegrass film by Alan Lomax, with George Pickow, cinematographer.
    - Good Old Times: The New Lost City Ramblers, rough cut, March 1, 2006, afc2011059_dc043; 1 DVD-R; 19 files (Box 84)
      Rough cut of a documentary about the New Lost City Ramblers.
    - NLCR documentary: Gone to the Country, Plywood Pictures, 2006, afc2011059_dc044; 1 DVD-R; 9 files (Box 84)
      Rough video files from the film Gone to the Country about the New Lost City Ramblers.
    - Folk Alliance video, Quicktime file, 2005, afc2011059_dc045; 1 DVD-R; 1 file (Box 84)
    - New Lost City Ramblers, sampler disc, March 09, 2007, afc2011059_dc046; 1 DVD-R; 9 files (Box 84)
      Video footage of New Lost City Ramblers performances, as well as Sara and Maybelle (Carter) film footage.
    - New Lost City Ramblers videos, last concert, Brandywine FOTM, May 15, 2009, afc2011059_dc047; 1 DVD-R; 59 files (Box 84)
      Video files of New Lost City Ramblers performing at Brandywine Friends of Old Time Music.
    - Berkeley Fiddler's Convention for John Cohen, 2006, afc2011059_dc048; 1 DVD-R; 10 files (Box 84)
      Video footage from the Berkeley Fiddler's Convention.
    - Berkeley Fiddler's Convention for John Cohen, Interviews, Tracy Schwarz and John Cohen, ca. 2006, afc2011059_dc049; 1 DVD-R; 10 files (Box 84)
      Video footage of interviews with John Cohen and Tracy Schwarz.
    - Berkeley Fiddler's Convention for John Cohen, ca. 2006, afc2011059_dc050; 1 DVD-R; 10 files (Box 84)
    - Berkeley Fiddler's Convention for John Cohen, Interviews, Mike Seeger, ca. 2006, afc2011059_dc051; 1 DVD-R; 10 files (Box 84)
      Video footage of interviews with Mike Seeger.
    - [New Lost City] Ramblers, sequence 1, February 13, 2007, afc2011059_dc052; 1 DVD-R; 9 files (Box 84)
      Video footage of and about the New Lost City Ramblers, some from the Berkeley Old Time Music Convention.
    - New Lost City Ramblers, sequences 2 and 3, February 28, 2007, afc2011059_dc053; 1 DVD-R; 14 files (Box 84)
    - Bill Cornett notes and JC web update, 2005, afc2011059_dc054; 1 CD-R; 2 files (Box 84)
      List of John Cohen publications and liner notes for Banjo Bill Cornett album.
    - Roscoe Holcomb, Kentucky 1959, tour 1966, photographs for LC, 1959-1966, afc2011059_dc055; 1 CD-R; 196 files (Box 84)
      John Cohen photographs (PDF format) in folders by general topic.
    - Roscoe film Hard Times, early edit, Undated, afc2011059_dc056; 1 DVD-R; 9 files (Box 84)
      Early edit of Hard Times film about Roscoe Holcomb (later became "High Lonesome Sound").
    - Interviews, John's copy (Geneve Gil, Cambridge, MA), 1989, afc2011059_dc057; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 2 files (Box 85)
      Written interviews with Jaime Guardia and Maria Alvarado Trujillo related to Peruvian/Quechua music.
    - Cohen interview, Sp-Eng translations (WordPerfect): Nan Volinsky, Urbana, IL, 1989, afc2011059_dc058; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 7 files (Box 85)
      Written interviews with people who worked at Huayno music record companies, and Nan Volinsky content.
    - Updated copy of files, Peru 2-4, intro and Palcha, Ithaca, W. final, changes, 1985, afc2011059_dc059; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Written music narration for Carnival in Q'eros film.
    - Copy of Peru music files - B: Peru 2, 3, 3A, 4, 5, 1985, afc2011059_dc060; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
    - Palcha and intro, 1983, afc2011059_dc061; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Written music narration for Mountain Music of Peru film.
    - Shapibo mss, 1987, afc2011059_dc062; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Writings and interview transcriptions about Peru and Shapibo painted cloth related to a film.
    - SUNY Purchase photography course materials, ca. 1986-1988, afc2011059_dc063; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Syllabus for Cohen's "History of Photography" course at SUNY Purchase; proposal for MFA program in photography; other course materials, including for course, "Looking at Photographs."
    - Research proposal and Boulton film materials, 1988, afc2011059_dc064; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Research grant proposal about traditional Peruvian folk music, as well as related correspondence.
    - Mountain Music of Peru narration, titles and subtitles, ca. 1984-1987, afc2011059_dc065; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
    - Film equipment lists and repairs, ca. 1988, afc2011059_dc066; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      List of tape recorders, film stock and tape, microphones, cameras, and other equipment for the making of Cohen's films.
    - John Cohen's CV and publications, ca. 1986, afc2011059_dc067; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
    - SUNY Purchase faculty meeting, 1985, afc2011059_dc068; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Meeting agenda, notes, and proposal for an MFA program in photography.
    - Pericles [in America] - publicity, distribution, 1988, afc2011059_dc069; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Publicity and distribution content for Cohen's film, Pericles in America.
    - Pericles [in America] - production, titles, 1988, afc2011059_dc070; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Introduction notes for Pericles in America, film sequences, descriptions, title and reel information, publicity, and fundraising.
    - Proposal for Pericles in America, 1987-1988, afc2011059_dc071; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Cover sheet by the New York City Foundation for the Arts proposing the making of Pericles in America.
    - Pericles [in America]: final reports, 1988, afc2011059_dc072; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Letter to New York Council for the Humanities asking for a grant extension, and descriptive information about the film.
    - Correspondence, 1987-1988, afc2011059_dc073; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Correspondence with Cohen and a variety of people, including faculty from SUNY Purchase, the Library of Congress Copyright office, and record label and radio professionals. Includes numerous requests for Cohen's materials.
    - Fulbright application, proposals, correspondence, 1987, afc2011059_dc074; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Writing on floppy disk: "Fulbright; film/music, article, Arhoolie - Peru." Materials for Fulbright application: proposal about Peruvian folk music and Quechua language radio. Proposal for an Arhoolie Records publication. Abstract for "Andean Music in the Peruvian Marketplace" project. Requests for letters of reference for Fulbright application.
    - Amsterdam conference, paper/AMNH (American Museum of Natural History) lecture, 1987-1988, afc2011059_dc075; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Analysis for exhibit on Andean music; correspondence about travel to Amsterdam for conference; lecture for American Museum of Natural History; music sequences to accompany Andean exhibitition.
    - Book reviews, NEA Peru application, 1987, afc2011059_dc076; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Book review of book about folk revival; agreement additions between Cohen and Ethnic Folk Arts regarding Pericles in America, plans and guidelines for distribution; proposal for research project on Peruvian folk music; NEA grant project summary and budget proposal.
    - Draft of Peruvian textile article, ca. 1985-1987, afc2011059_dc077; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Writing on disk: "Haffenreffer final." Paper/article by Cohen titled, "The Study of Ethnographic Textiles in Peru: a Personal View."
    - Letters, projects, 1987, afc2011059_dc078; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Ideas for paper at Costume as Communication conference, Haffenreffer Museum, Margot Schevill; draft of "An Overview of the Study of Ethnographic Textiles"; letters of recommendation/reference.
    - NEA final report, 1987, afc2011059_dc079; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Final report on NEA Folk Arts Grant for Pericles in America.
    - NEH 2, 1987, afc2011059_dc080; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Proposal for Pericles in America.
    - NEH application; Pericles [in America], copy and revision, 1986-1987, afc2011059_dc081; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      NEH application drafts and correspondence related to the making of Pericles in America.
    - Film projects, ca. 1985-1987, afc2011059_dc082; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Listing and descriptions of Cohen's film projects, as well as correspondence; appraisal of ethnographic film collection for potential donation to Lincoln Center.
    - Pericles in America, NEA folk, NYSCA (New York State Council on the Arts), 1987, afc2011059_dc085; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
    - "Notes from a Filmmaker" article about Andean music film, ca. 1985, afc2011059_dc086; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Article drafts for Folklife Annual, and related correspondence.
    - The Woman's Building article draft and notes, Undated, afc2011059_dc087; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Woman's Building article draft and notes; feminist Fables by Suniti Namjoshi, published in England in 1981.
    - Letters, ca. 1985-1987, afc2011059_dc088; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Partial CV for John Cohen, and correspondence, including publication requests and letters of recommendation for graduate students.
    - Copy of all Peru music files, August 12, 1985, afc2011059_dc089; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Drafts of article on Andean music. Includes correspondence with Billie Jean Isbell, and lists of Q'eros recordings from cassettes used for Cohen's films and albums about Andean music.
    - Rufus, 1986, afc2011059_dc090; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Letters to Rufus Cohen.
    - Correspondence and career materials, ca. 1985-1987, afc2011059_dc091; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Career information, CVs, and correspondence about Peruvian and other films; film project descriptions, writings, and promotional materials.
    - Writing about Q'eros, Undated, afc2011059_dc093; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Short writing about Q'eros music.
    - Writing about Huayno music and the Q'eros, Undated, afc2011059_dc097; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Possibly related to Mountain Music of Peru documentary film. File includes computer software information.
    - Q'ero chart text, Undated, afc2011059_dc099; 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch); 2 files (Box 85)
      Writings for movie stills; calendar of Q'ero life activities.
    - Q'eros textile book, Undated, afc2011059_dc100; 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Notes about John Cohen's work with the Q'eros; notes from Ann Rowe meeting.
    - Q'eros images, Undated, afc2011059_dc101; 1 floppy disk (3.5 inch); 4 files (Box 85)
      Text file relating to Q'eros book.
    - Damian, Directora, Alanya, John: originals (formatted ok w/ DOS 3.10), 1989-1990, afc2011059_dc102; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 4 files (Box 85)
      Image files relating to Q'eros trip. Note: the files are corrupted and missing portions.
    - Interview with Leo Casas by John Cohen about Peruvian music, 1980, afc2011059_dc103; 1 floppy disk (5.25 inch); 1 file (Box 85)
      Question and answer with four folklorists, including John Cohen.
  - Subseries 12. Artifacts, undated
    - Banjo, undated, afc2011059_ar01; 1 5-string banjo
      Banjo that belonged to John Cohen but was commonly played by Kentucky banjoist Roscoe Holcomb. Holcomb played the banjo on his High Lonesome Sound album on Smithsonian Folkways.